GHADA MAHGOUB



- Dubai, UAE
- +971 55 8656056
- ghidden2001@yahoo.com
- Egyptian

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hospitality professional with solid experience in various functions and divisions of the hotel industry. Excellent & proven track record in management & team-leading skills well versed with executive office & board members. Highly energetic, detailed oriented enthusiastic person with clear decision-making abilities, motivator, leading by example and always looking forward to new goals and challenges.

WORK HISTORY

Hotel Manager 03/2018 - 05/2020

SRG Hospitality – Pre opening of "Staybridge Suites Dubai Internet City by IHG- 225 Suites & Apartments

(known earlier as :AlSalam Grand Hotel & Hotel Apartments)
Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Brief about the role:-

I was appointed by SRG group to be in charge to seize the operation of the previous brand that managed the building and bring it under the owner's hospitality portfolio. Property was renamed as "AlSalam Grand Hotel & Hotel Apartments", managed by SRG hospitality. The hotel run full operation till owner signed the franchise deal with IHG Group to be converted to "Staybridge Suites", an extended stay brand of IHG Group.

While 50% of the property is under renovation to comply with the new brand requirements, the hotel is still operating under the owner brand with which my responsibilities included the following: -

- Ensure smooth operation is on place for all in-house guests during the renovation and transition period.
- Drive improvement in guest satisfaction goals through collaboration with hotel team members to establish and implement services & programs that meet and exceed guest expectations.
- Close monitor of the sales team performance and their market contact, ensure that they drive business to the property.
- Prepare and present detailed monthly P&L to the owner office.

<u>Meanwhile</u> with the renovation & rebranding preparation, my responsibilities included: -

- Overlook the renovation progress and attend the weekly project meeting.
- Arrange all legal requirements for hotel tourism and commercial licenses.
- Arrange and coordinate with IHG team for on boarding requirements.
- Fully in charge of the pre-opening critical path and update IHG concerned team on the progress accordingly.
- Prepare annual capital, cash flow and Sales & Marketing plans to accurately forecast budget.

Hotel Manager 04/2017 - 02/2018

Time Asma Hotel, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Pre-opening Project- 215 Rooms

My role: to coordinate with the hotel owner & Management Company for the requirements of:

- Hotel Mock up Room: Design, furniture, accessories / Hotel Outlets including Banquet
- Follow up with the project consultant to finalize the approval needed from all government sectors & authorities.
- Coordinate with the main contractor to finalize all the requirements for property MEP and property function systems (PMS, GRMS, BMS).

Executive Assistant Manager 05/ 2016 - 04/2017
Yassat Gloria Hotel & Hotel Apartments -1019 Suites & Apartments
(Rebranded currently as "Mercure Barsha Heights"), Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Fully in charge of Hotel operation, Guest satisfaction & Team performance and all related communication to the hotel owner office. Hotel headcount: 450 team members.

Achievements: -

GOP: 52% (104 % VS Budget) - Guest Satisfaction: 80 % on target (100%) - Colleague Satisfaction: 82% (103% VS Budget) - CSR activities: Green Globe Certificate.

Director of Rooms 02/2014 - 05/2016

Yassat Gloria Hotel & Hotel Apartments, Dubai, UAE

Fully responsible and accountable for: Housekeeping, Front Office, Security & Recreation departments. (Head count: 265 Team members).

-Substitution of the Hotel General Manger (09/2014-01/2015)

In Charge of Hotel full operation; Managed to achieve all scores and Higher than target goals:-

Guest Satisfaction: 102% - Gross Operation Profit: 112%

Training hours: 150 hour per team.

Front Office Manager 11/2012 - 02/2014 Yassat Gloria Hotel & Hotel Apartments, Dubai, UAE Pre-opening phase

In charge of security & recreation departments during opening process.

- Prepare the manning and budget for each department.
- Arrange and draft long term stays contracts, payment and stay procedures
- Managed to rent the hotel retail area to third party partners include: hair dresser salon, rent a car desk, and jewelry shop.

Front Office Manager 11/2011 - 11/2012

Gloria Hotel & Hotel Apartments -1000 Suites & Apartments

(Rebranded currently as "Two Seasons Hotel & Hotel Apartments") Dubai, UAE

Front Office Manager 04/2010 - 11/2011

Novotel Resort Sharm El Sheikh, Sharm El Sheikh, Egypt

Cluster role for Novotel the Palm & Novotel Beach Resort – 550 Rooms

Front Office Manager 05/2009 - 03/2010 Hilton Sharm Dreams Resort, (498 unites), Sharm El Sheikh, Egypt, 227 rooms, 151 villas.

Cluster Front Office Manager 08/2007 - 01/2009 Hilton Ras Al Khaimah Hotel, Resort & Spa

Ras Al Khaimah, United Arab Emirates

Responsibilities:-

- Preparation for the opening of the second phase for "Hilton Ras Al Khaimah Resort & Spa".
- Coordinate with contractors for a mock up room view including all the equipment, furniture / SOE and present the same for GM approval.
- Full snag of the mock up rooms and arranged all requirements for the back of the house & administration offices

Front Office Manager 09/2003 - 08/2007

Hilton Fujairah Resort, Fujairah, United Arab Emirates
In charge of Revenue and Sales departments

Hilton Cairo Ramses, Cairo, Egypt

Various positions:

 Groups & Events Manager
 03/1999 - 08/2001

 Group Reservations Supervisor
 03/1997 - 03/1999.

 Groups & Events Coordinator
 01/1996 - 03/1997.

 Telephone Operator
 11/1992 - 01/1996

SKILLS

- Customer oriented
- Revenue management
- Budgets and cost control
- Team leader: Lead by example
- Innovative
- Creative
- Project Leadership & Project oversight

TRAINING

- Cornell University: Certificate of "Project Leadership"
- IHG General Manager Program
- Creative Thinking & Critical Analysis by "Accor".

Trainings Courses by Hilton International

- The OZ principle
- Emotional Intelligence in the Work Place
- Strategies for Analysis
- IDEAS (Revenue Management System)
- Advanced presentation skills
- Dynamic People Management
- Proactive Leadership
- Commercial Management
- Maximizing Reservation Revenue
- Banquet & Conference, Sales and Administration
- Yield, Revenue Management

Hilton University courses: complete more than 200 courses online

EDUCATION

Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt, 1991

BA: English Literature & Culture